

CONTACT ME

- London, UK
- +44(0)7368 157 862
- www.blakebdavies.com 🚺 blakebdavies

ABOUT ME

Dynamic and meticulous web developer with front-end experience and passion for turning complex problems into simple, beautiful and intuitive designs. I am a firm believer in the mobile-first approach and utilize modern front-end technologies including HTML, CSS, Javascript, and React framework to bring ideas to life in the browser. With over 8 years of experience across the UK and US, I aim to ally my wealth of expertise and passion for innovation to new and exciting opportunities.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, GitHub, CodeSandbox, Netlify, VS Code, Bootstrap, API integration, NPM, Responsive Web Design, Figma, InVisionApp, Testing and Debugging, WordPress, Squarespace, and Shopify

INTERESTS

- I enjoy learning languages. I am fluent in Spanish and have studied Italian and Mandarin to an intermediate level.
- When I'm not pushing pixels, you can find me exploring galleries, museums, and street art.
- Throughout lockdown, I have become an avid cinephile.
- I am a life-long athlete and play tennis weekly.
- Fueled daily by coffee and crosswords.

BLAKE DAVIES

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Operations Manager

Brush and Bubbles, Ltd. | Sept. 2019-present

- Leading website development engineering large-scale website transition and using HTML and CSS to optimize e-commerce opportunities.
- Translating UX wireframes into code that will update the front end, and building reusable code for future application.
- Ensuring that web design is optimized for mobile.
- Creating intuitive user interfaces using responsive HTML and CSS through the product development cycle.
- Co-ordinating and managing general digital and marketing strategies.

Account Manager

Brickfish Social Listening and Publishing | Dec.2015 - Aug.2017

- Project planning and execution throughout the product lifecycle gathering client requirements, defining the vision, and working across teams to meet client
- · Managing design teams and engineers in the development and maintenance of media software to enable clients to build, manage and monitor their digital engagements and ROI.
- Supporting on website development for key clients, and ensuring the technical implementation of UI/UX designs.
- Collaborating with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Sotheby's Institute of Art; University of Manchester

MA in Art Business, Sept. 2017 - May 2019

• Director's Commendation & First Class Honours with Distinction

Lake Forest College

BA in International Relations, Economics & Asian Studies, Aug. 2010 - May 2014

• Semester Study of Rural Economics, Sino-American Relations, and Chinese Language & Culture at Peking University, Spring 2013

CERTIFICATIONS

SheCodes: React Framework

SheCodes Workshop, June 2021

SheCodes: Responsive Website Development

SheCodes Workshop, May 2021

SheCodes: Front-End Development

SheCodes Workshop, April 2021

SheCodes: Introduction to Coding

SheCodes Workshop, February 2021